# Damilola Seweje John

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

sewejed@gmail.com

<u>Twitter</u> | <u>GitHib</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

+234 806 943 2293



Performance-driven, motivated and self-taught Full Stack Developer with extensive experience in participating in all phases of web development. Possess strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and the ability to complete all projects within schedule and on time.

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript, Typescript, React, Node, MongoDB, Firebase, Git, Heroku, HTML5, CSS3 (SASS), RestFul APIs, GraphQL

## **EXPERIENCE**

Freelancer, Full Stack developer (2017 - Current)

- Developed and hosted static portfolio websites using HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), Vanilla JavaScript
- Implemented a full dashboard that manages users, employees, keeps track of expenses, maps users to different locations.
- Developed and deployed websites with payment features using React.
- Developed an SMS sending service that notifies clients and also has payment features using Nodeis and MongoDB for the database.

### CROWN INTERACTIVE LTD, Frontend developer (2019 - 2021)

- Implemented the UI for a Customer Management System. An application for managing customer's orders and tracking purchases and expenses.
- Responsible for developing a product (<u>cicod.com</u>), a SAAS entry application for both small and large businesses. React was used to develop the app which includes features like pricing, free trial subscription, a dashboard for management of product purchased and many other features.
- Developed several email templates for products notifications.

### ENERGY DETECTORS, Full Stack developer (May 2020 - November 2020)

- Developed secured services (private and public) that tracks electricity usage, the outage and supply duration from a device attached to the source of electricity users using Nodejs and Firebase as a database.
- Developed email notification services

- Developed a web app for purchasing products (sensors) from the company
- Developed a dashboard for the public API, for tracking request making purchases.

JAMSELECT HQ (jamselect.com), Frontend developer (October 2020 - April 2021)

 Responsible for creating UI components and implementation of features by consuming services, using React and GraphQL

BIZ 301, Frontend developer (August 2020 - April 2021)

• Responsible for creating UI components.

### **PROJECTS**

**URL Shortener application** 

**PhonyJS** 

A mini backend framework using Node and Typescript

Plearn (In Development)

- An E-learning application that determines student's learners' learning styles and recommends courses based on individual learning styles.
- Built with: (React, Material UI, Typescript, MongoDB, Nodejs, Heroku)

## **EDUCATION**

Senior Secondary Certificate of Education (SSCE), (2009 -2014)

Beccy-Jo College

B-Tech In Mathematical Sciences, (2015 -20202)

Federal University of Technology Akure